<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>grad_school_admission on Ramble On</title><link>https://nishchayp.github.io/blog/categories/grad_school_admission/</link><description>Recent content in grad_school_admission on Ramble On</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>nishchayparashar98@gmail.com (Nishchay Parashar)</managingEditor><webMaster>nishchayparashar98@gmail.com (Nishchay Parashar)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 12:13:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nishchayp.github.io/blog/categories/grad_school_admission/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>For those Undergrads who have Grad School on their mind</title><link>https://nishchayp.github.io/blog/posts/grad_school_admission/advice_to_ugs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 12:13:28 -0400</pubDate><author>nishchayparashar98@gmail.com (Nishchay Parashar)</author><guid>https://nishchayp.github.io/blog/posts/grad_school_admission/advice_to_ugs/</guid><description>This is just some advice from a current grad school student on what you should work on and (more importantly) what you should not work on during your undergrad years if grad school is your aim. I&amp;rsquo;m currently pursuing a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science at Brown University and while I was applying to all these various grad school programs there was a constant frustration (maybe &amp;lsquo;frustration&amp;rsquo; is too heavy a word, but I guess you get my point) on what all things I could have done better during my undergrad along with the sporadic moments of relief thinking about things I did right.</description></item><item><title>A (My) Grad School Program shortlisting strategy</title><link>https://nishchayp.github.io/blog/posts/grad_school_admission/program_shortlisting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 15:56:03 -0400</pubDate><author>nishchayparashar98@gmail.com (Nishchay Parashar)</author><guid>https://nishchayp.github.io/blog/posts/grad_school_admission/program_shortlisting/</guid><description>My totally non-scientific methodology of shortlisting grad programs, specifically master&amp;rsquo;s programs, that kinda works (or at least did for me)!
This blog post is in all honesty a true ramble, this was actually a text conversation with a friend of mine which I am now converting into a blog post.
Everyone applying to grad school has and for eternity (probably!) will struggle with program shortlisting. There are some who have a few very specific programs in mind and to those people congratulations you really are awesome and do not need to read this further whereas for others like me who are not constrained by having a niche interest we all try to make a list of program and divide that list into the tried and tested safe-moderate-ambitious categories.</description></item><item><title>Finally done with the GRE. Testing experience, prep plan, and more...</title><link>https://nishchayp.github.io/blog/posts/grad_school_admission/gre_experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 15:19:01 -0400</pubDate><author>nishchayparashar98@gmail.com (Nishchay Parashar)</author><guid>https://nishchayp.github.io/blog/posts/grad_school_admission/gre_experience/</guid><description>Finally, finally, finally done with the GRE. Didn&amp;rsquo;t do too shabby, scored:
169 Quant :) 160 Verbal :/ 3.5AWA :( A little context, I&amp;rsquo;m a non-native English speaker and would be applying for MS in CS programs. Also, I prepared for 6 months along with a 40hrs per week internship, though the pandemic lockdown helped me focus pretty much completely on GRE for the last month. This was my testing experience and preparation material and plan I followed:</description></item></channel></rss>